MATEUSZ ZAREMBA

Wroclaw, Poland

Phone: +48 570 768 552

Email: matzaremba@icloud.com

GitHub: https://github.com/matzar

Portfolio: https://matzar.github.io

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mateusz-zaremba/

Personal Profile

A highly motivated and enthusiastic individual with 3 years of learning experience in C++ 11/14/17 and Unity3D programming plus almost 1 year of professional software and game development; skilled in agile, pair and SCRUM software development, able to adapt to any given situation with a professional approach. Learns quickly using existing experience and environments, to integrate as a productive member of a team. Employs strong organisational skills, ever ready to learn and develop new skills and is always happy to take a flexible approach to work. Works to target effectively and possesses analytical and organisational skills together with excellent written and oral communication.

Technical Skills

Core:

- <u>C++</u>
- Unity3D with C#
- Unreal Engine 4
- Visual Studio, Xcode, VS Code, Atom
- github BASH, git SVN, SVN
- JIRA, Confluence, Crucible, Bamboo

Additional:

- OpenGL 1.1
- DirectX 11 HLSL
- Networking with SFML/UE4
- PSVita with Box2D using C++
- Face emotion recognition semi-ML
- SQL
- Visual Novel made with Ren'Py using Python

Education

University of Abertay Dundee, United Kingdom:

2015 – 2018 Bachelor of Science in Computer Game Applications Development, 2:1 (HEAR):

3rd year modules (GPA: 2.83):

- Graphics Programming with Shaders (C+)
- Gameplay Mechanics Development (C+)
- Network Systems for Game Development (A)
- Artificial Intelligence (B)
- Professional Team Project: Planning and Prototyping (C+)
- Professional Team Project: Development and Delivery (C+)

2nd year modules (GPA: 4.17)

- Data Structures and Algorithms 1 (A)
- Data Structures and Algorithms 2 (A+)
- Graphics Programming (A)
- Game Programming and System Architectures (A)
- Film and Game Genres (A)
- Mathematics for Application Development 2 (A+)

1st year modules (GPA: 3.63):

- Computer and Graphics Architectures (A)
- Programming in C++ (A)
- Narrative Theory in Interactive Game Design (C+)
- Mathematics for Applications Development 1 (A+)
- Asset Production for Games (B+)
- Games for Change (B+)

Sep 2015 - Jul 2018:

- Member of Abertay Game Development Society (git: 1st year, 2nd year)

Sep 2015 - Apr 2016:

- Class Representative for 1st Year Computer Applications Game Development course

Relevant Experience

01.2019 - 02.2019: C++ Software Engineer Intern, First Line Software

- Design and implementation of large distributed IT systems according to customer and project requirements.
- Quick and efficient concept creation and prototyping of new solutions.
- Close co-operation with product management to understand the requirements of customers and deliver the agreed solution on time
- Testing of the developed solution

08.2018 - 10.2018: Unreal Game Programmer Intern, Bohemia Interactive

- Project worked on Vigor ([video] update I worked on), post-apocalyptic survival game
- Engine: UE4 | Platform: XBOX ONE

Key responsibilities:

- Networked gameplay programming
- UI programming
- Developing new solutions based on already existing ones and bug fixing

09.2017 - 06.2018: Lead Programme, Abertay University: Professional Project

- Project worked on Mobile game for Junkfish Game Company | Retro platformer for Timex company (git)
- Engine: Unity | Programming language: C# | Platforms: Android (Junk Fish) | Windows (Timex)

Key responsibilities:

- Prototyping and gameplay programming
- Source control maintenance (merging, pull requests, .gitignore)
- Programming team management using GitHub Projects with kanban board, SCRUM (Deadlines setting, mentoring)

Game Jams

24.01.2018 - 26.01.2018: Gameplay Programmer/Design/Team Lead, Serious Game Jam

- Mobile game prototype aiding lectures and students at the University of St Andrews with practical exercises preparation and explanation
- Engine: Unity | Programming language: C# | Platform: Android (video link, git)

15.11.2017: Gameplay Programmer/Design/Team Lead, AGDS 4-hour Game Jam

- Brief visual novel with animations, presenting a joke, made in 4-hours with two artists
- Engine: Ren'Py | Programming language: Python | Platform: Windows (video link, git)

15.08.2016 - 17.08.2016: Gameplay Programmer/Design/Team Lead, Rainbow Game Jam

- Infinite runner chosen to be made in 48-hours with two other artists and a sound designer
- Engine: Unity | Programming language: C# | Platforms: Windows, MAC, Linux (video link, git, play game)

29.01.2016 - 31.01.2016: Gameplay Programmer, Global Game Jam 2016

- Easy pick-up game. My first Unity game and first game jam
- Engine: Unity | Programming language: C# | Platforms: Windows, MAC, Linux (video link)

Other Experience

Oct 2015 - Dec 2015: Warden, St. Ninian's Institute, Diocese of Dunkeld

- Taking care of the St Ninian's Institute and its guests; welcoming them at the reception and showing to the room.
- Overall maintenance: checking heaters, creating online calendar, reacting to any emergencies

Apr 2015 – Aug 2015: Waiter/Bartender, Drumoig Golf Hotel

 Working behind the bar, waiting tables and welcoming people at the hotel while maintaining professional approach in every situation

May 2013 - Aug 2013: Office Assistant, University of Wroclaw

- Calling vendors to set up appointments and gather information, delivering post, helping out in the office with various tasks

Jan 2009 – Aug 2009: Younger Lifeguard, Wroclaw Water Park

- Taking care of visitors safety and well being. Stamina and health training. Took part in a solo rescue action

Hobbies and interests:

In my spare time I like to go for long walks and play squash. I also keep up to date with current technologies and affairs.